<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><plecoflash formatversion="2" creator="Pleco User 19105471" generator="Pleco 2.0 Flashcard Exporter" platform="iPhone OS" created="1690315838"><cards><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689690343"><entry><headword charset="sc">难</headword><headword charset="tc">難</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">nan2</pron><defn>adjective 1 difficult; hard; troublesome (opp. 易) 很难想象 Hěn nán xiǎngxiàng (it’s) hard to imagine 山路难走。 Shānlù nán zǒu. Mountain paths are hard to travel. 说起来容易做起来难。 Shuō qǐlai róngyì zuò qǐlai nán. Easier said than done. 这道题很难解。 zhè dào tí hěn nán jiě. This problem is hard to solve. 2 hardly possible; unavoidable See 27188992难免nan2mian3难免 3 bad; unpleasant 这种啤酒真难喝。 zhèzhǒng píjiǔ zhēn nán hē. This beer tastes really bad. 
verb put sb. into a difficult position 这问题一下子把我难住了。 Zhè wèntí yīxiàzi bǎ wǒ nán zhù le. The question put me on the spot.</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="27183104"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 3"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="84" history="5154" correct="3" incorrect="1" reviewed="4" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689690614" lastreviewedtime="1690296433"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689690497"><entry><headword charset="sc">容易</headword><headword charset="tc">容易</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">rong2yi4</pron><defn>adjective 1 easy 好(不)容易 hǎobùróngyì not at all easy; in a hard way 容易的题先做。 Róngyì de tí xiān zuò. Do the easy problems first. 说起来容易做起来难。 Shuō qǐlai róngyì zuò qǐlai nán. It’s easier said than done. 2 likely; liable; apt 他容易生病。 Tā róngyì shēngbìng. He often gets ill. 这容易引起误会。 Zhè róngyì yǐnqǐ wùhuì. This is liable to cause misunderstanding. 人们容易把这两个问题混淆起来。 Rénmen róngyì bǎ zhè liǎng ge wèntí hùnxiáo qǐlai. People are apt to confuse the two issues.</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="29114112"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 3"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 3"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="55111" correct="2" incorrect="3" reviewed="5" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689690654" lastreviewedtime="1690089633"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686177838" modified="1689690543"><entry><headword charset="sc">过来</headword><headword charset="tc">過來</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">//guo5//lai5</pron><defn>verb 1 [with 得 or 不 to indicate the sufficiency or insufficiency of time, capability or quantity] can handle; can deal with 参考书太多, 简直看不过来。 Cānkǎoshū tài duō, jiǎnzhí kàn bù guolai. There are just too many reference books. I simply can’t read them all. 孩子多了照顾不过来。 Háizi duō le zhàogu bù guolai. If you have too many children, you won&apos;t be able to care for them all properly. 你一个人忙得过来吗？ Nǐ yī ge rén máng de guolai ma？ Can you manage by yourself? 2 [indicating motion towards the speaker] towards; up 捷报从四面八方飞 过来。 Jiébào cóng sìmiàn-bāfāng fēi guolai. News of success kept pouring in from all directions. 一队士兵正朝我们走过来。 Yī duì shìbīng zhèng cháo wǒmen zǒu guolai. A contingent of soldiers was marching towards us. 3 [indicating turning towards the speaker] 他转过脸来, 我才认出是位老同学。 Tā zhuǎn guò liǎn lái, wǒ cái rènchū shì wèi lǎo tóngxué. He turned around, and I recognized him as a former classmate. 请你转过来让我量量胸围。 Qǐng nǐ zhuǎn guolai ràng wǒ liàng liàng xiōngwéi. Please turn round and let me measure your chest. 4 [indicating a return to the normal state] come round 醒过来 Xǐng guolai wake up; sober up; come to 觉悟过来 Juéwù guòlai see the light; realize; elucidate 他的坏习惯一定得改过来。 Tā de huài xíguàn yī dìng děi gǎi guolai. His bad habits must be changed. 他真固执, 简直劝不过来。 Tā zhēn gùzhí, jiǎnzhí quàn bù guolai. He’s really stubborn and won’t be persuaded. 爬到山顶, 大家都累得喘不过气来。 Pá dào shāndǐng, dàjiā dōu lèi de chuǎn bù guò qì lái. We were all out of breath when we reached the mountain peak.</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="22223104"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="608" difficulty="96" history="554" correct="3" incorrect="0" reviewed="3" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689690646" lastreviewedtime="1690089985"/></card><card language="english" created="1689631509" modified="1689690543"><entry><headword charset="sc">already</headword><headword charset="tc">already</headword></entry><dictref dictid="1347367493" entryid="16334848"/><catassign category="Custom"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689735767"><entry><headword charset="sc">从</headword><headword charset="tc">從</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">cong2</pron><defn>verb 1 follow; comply with; obey 从大流 cóng dà liú follow the general public 2 join; be engaged in See 19188736从军cong2jun1从军 3 follow the principle of; employ the method of 训练要从严从难。 Xùnliàn yào cóngyán cóng nán. Training should be hard and strict. 
noun dated 1 follower; attendant 从人 cóngrén followers; retinue 2 relationship between cousins, etc. of the same paternal grandfather or great-grandfather 从兄弟 cóng xiōng-dì cousins on the paternal side; cousins 
adjective secondary; accessary 主从关系 zhǔcóng guānxi principal and subordinate relations 
preposition 1 from (a time, a place, or a point of view) 从零开始 cóng líng kāishǐ start from scratch (or nothing) 从现在起 cóng xiànzài qǐ from now on 从根本上说 cóng gēnběn shàng shuō essentially; in essence 从全局出发 cóng quánjú chūfā proceed from the situation as a whole 从这儿往西 cóng zhèr wǎng xī go west from here; west of here 从我做起, 从现在做起。 cóng wǒ zuòqǐ, cóng xiànzài zuòqǐ. Begin from myself, and begin right now. 2 via, through, or past (a place) 从门缝里往外看 cóng ménfèng lǐ wǎng wài kàn peep outside through a crevice in the door 从学校门前经过 Cóng xuéxiào mén qián jīngguò pass the school gate 你从桥上过, 我从桥下走。 Nǐ cóng qiáo shàng guò, wǒ cóng qiáo xià zǒu. You go over the bridge, I’ll go under it. 
adverb [followed by a negative] ever 从不计较个人的名誉地位 Cóngbù jìjiào gèrén de míngyù dìwèi never give any consideration to personal fame or position 从没听说过。 Cóng méi tīngshuō guò. Never heard of it. 她在成绩面前从不骄傲。 Tā zài chéngjì miànqián cóngbù jiāo&apos;ào. Her head was never turned by success.</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19185152"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 2"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="5551" correct="3" incorrect="1" reviewed="4" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777902" lastreviewedtime="1690089630"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689735773"><entry><headword charset="sc">第</headword><headword charset="tc">第</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">di4</pron><defn>affix [before numerals to form ordinal numbers] 《第五交响曲》 《Dì-wǔ Jiāoxiǎngqǔ》 The Fifth Symphony; Symphony No. 5 《宪法》第三条 xiànfǎ dì-sān tiáo Article 3 of the Constitution 
adverb literary but; only 第恐 dì kǒng I only fear that... 
noun 1 archaic different grades of successful candidates in the imperial examinations 及第 jídì pass an imperial examination 2 literary residence of a high official 府第 fǔdì mansion house 
conjunction classical but; however</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19942656"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="1098" difficulty="100" history="565" correct="3" incorrect="0" reviewed="3" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777843" lastreviewedtime="1690296440"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689735774"><entry><headword charset="sc">页</headword><headword charset="tc">頁</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ye4</pron><defn>noun page; leaf 活页 huóyè loose-leaf 
measure word leaf; page; sheet 一本三百页的书 Yī běn sānbǎi yè de shū a book of three hundred pages</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="34305024"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 4"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="5611" correct="2" incorrect="2" reviewed="4" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777934" lastreviewedtime="1690089613"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178464" modified="1689735781"><entry><headword charset="sc">语法</headword><headword charset="tc">語法</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">yu3fa3</pron><defn>noun grammar 教学语法 jiàoxué yǔfǎ pedagogical grammar 实用语法 shíyòng yǔfǎ practical grammar 描述语法 miáo shù yǔ fǎ descriptive grammar 规定语法 guīdìng yǔfǎ prescriptive grammar 不符合语法的句子 bù fúhé yǔfǎ de jùzi ungrammatical sentence</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="35249920"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 4"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 4"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="561" correct="2" incorrect="1" reviewed="3" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777861" lastreviewedtime="1690089637"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689735787"><entry><headword charset="sc">开始</headword><headword charset="tc">開始</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">kai1shi3</pron><defn>noun beginning; outset; commencement 一开始 yī kāishǐ at the very beginning 一种新的工作, 开始总会遇到一些困难。 Yī zhǒng xīn de gōngzuò, kāishǐ zǒng huì yùdào yīxiē kùnnan. You always run into some difficulties at the beginning of a new job. 
verb begin; start; commence 开始生效 kāishǐ shēngxiào take effect; come into effect (or force) 从头开始 cóngtóu kāishǐ start from the very beginning 开始讨论实质性问题 Kāishǐ tǎolùn shízhìxìng wèntí come to substantive questions 今天从第五课开始。 Jīntiān cóng dì-wǔ kè kāishǐ. Today we’ll begin with Lesson 5. 他们开始了旅行中最危险的阶段。 Tāmenkāishǐ le lǚxíng zhōng zuì wēixiǎn de jiēduàn. They entered upon the most dangerous part of the journey.</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="24819456"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 3"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 2"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="52611" correct="2" incorrect="3" reviewed="5" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777886" lastreviewedtime="1690296463"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689735817"><entry><headword charset="sc">作业</headword><headword charset="tc">作業</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zuo4ye4</pron><defn>noun school assignment; homework 改作业 gǎi zuòyè correct students’ papers; correct homework 做作业 zuò zuòyè do one’s assignment; do homework 
verb work; task; operation 水下作业 shuǐ xià zuòyè underwater operation 野外作业 yěwài zuòyè fieldwork; field operation 农业主要作业的机械化 nóngyè zhǔyào zuòyède jīxièhuà mechanization of all major farm operations</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="37160704"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 2"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 3"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="5521" correct="2" incorrect="2" reviewed="4" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777877" lastreviewedtime="1690089627"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689735904"><entry><headword charset="sc">复习</headword><headword charset="tc">複習</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">fu4xi2</pron><defn>verb review; revise 复习功课 fùxí gōngkè review (or revise) lessons</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="21298944"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 2"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 3"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="561" correct="2" incorrect="1" reviewed="3" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777909" lastreviewedtime="1690089621"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689735906"><entry><headword charset="sc">请</headword><headword charset="tc">請</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">qing3</pron><defn>verb 1 request; ask 请人来修机器 Qǐng rén lái xiū jīqì get sb. to repair the machine; get the machine repaired 请他进来。 Qǐng tā jìnlai. Ask him in. 请你多加指导。 Qǐng nǐ duō jiā zhǐdǎo. It is hoped you will give us guidance. 2 invite; engage 请医生 qǐng yīshēng send for a doctor 请总工程师来讲课 qǐng zǒnggōngchéngshī lái jiǎngkè invite the chief engineer to give a lecture 3 courteous please 请坐。 Qǐngzuò. Won’t you sit down? or Please be seated. 请安静。 Qǐng ānjìng. Be quiet, please. 请速回信。 Qǐngsùhuíxìn. Please reply as soon as possible. 4 dated buy holy sacrificial things, such as joss sticks, candles, paper horses and Buddha shrines</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="28669952"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 1"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="52211" correct="1" incorrect="4" reviewed="5" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777929" lastreviewedtime="1690296453"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689735912"><entry><headword charset="sc">笔记</headword><headword charset="tc">筆記</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">bi3ji4</pron><defn>noun 1 notes 记笔记 Jì bǐjì take notes 核对笔记 héduì bǐjì check notes; verify notes 2 pen jottings (a type of literature consisting mainly of short sketches) 《阅微草堂笔记》 《Yuè Wēi Cǎotáng Bǐjì》 Jottings from the Thatched Abode of Close Observations (by Ji Yun (纪昀, 1724-1805)) 
verb take down (in writing) 按口述笔记 àn kǒushù bǐjì write from dictation</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="17477120"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 2"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="51521" correct="2" incorrect="3" reviewed="5" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777893" lastreviewedtime="1690296460"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178464" modified="1689735938"><entry><headword charset="sc">棒</headword><headword charset="tc">棒</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">bang4</pron><defn>noun stick; club; cudgel 木棒 mùbàng wooden stick 垒球棒 lěiqiú bàng softball bat 
adjective colloquial good; fine; excellent; strong 棒小伙子 Bàng xiǎohuǒzi a strong young fellow 字写得棒 zì xiě de bàng write a good hand 你干得棒极了。 Nǐ gàn de bàng jíle. You’ve done a first-rate job. 庄稼长得真棒。 Zhuāngjia zhǎng de zhēn bàng. The crops are excellent.</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="17191168"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 5"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 4"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="51211" correct="1" incorrect="4" reviewed="5" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689777851" lastreviewedtime="1690296421"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689828375"><entry><headword charset="sc">姐姐</headword><headword charset="tc">姐姐</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">jie3jie5</pron><defn>noun elder sister; sister</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="24167424"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 2"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="1097" difficulty="100" history="55" correct="2" incorrect="0" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689828811" lastreviewedtime="1690296412"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689865572"><entry><headword charset="sc">北</headword><headword charset="tc">北</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">bei3</pron><defn>noun 1 north 城北 chéng běi north of the city 往北走 wǎng běi zǒu go north 朝北的房间 Cháo běi de fángjiān room facing the north 2 the North (the developed countries) 南北对话 Nán-Běi Duìhuà North-South dialogue 
verb literary be defeated 连战皆北 liánzhànjiēběi repeatedly defeated in battle; suffer repeated defeats</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="17338368"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="1039" difficulty="100" history="55" correct="2" incorrect="0" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903666" lastreviewedtime="1690296506"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689865579"><entry><headword charset="sc">南</headword><headword charset="tc">南</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">nan2</pron><defn>noun 1 south 南屋 nánwū room facing south 城南 Chéng nán southern part of the city 2 (Nán) a surname</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="27166208"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 3"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="100" difficulty="88" history="111" correct="0" incorrect="3" reviewed="3" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903701" lastreviewedtime="1690296428"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689878845"><entry><headword charset="sc">没错</headword><headword charset="tc">沒錯</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">mei2cuo4</pron><defn>1 that&apos;s right 2 sure! 3 rest assured! 4 that&apos;s good 5 can&apos;t go wrong</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="9807360"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 4"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="88" history="511" correct="1" incorrect="2" reviewed="3" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903757" lastreviewedtime="1690296438"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689879139"><entry><headword charset="sc">抱</headword><headword charset="tc">抱</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">bao4</pron><defn>verb 1 hold or carry in the arms; embrace; hug 抱着小孩子 bào zhe xiǎoháizi take a child in one’s arms 不要抱住错误观点不放。 Bùyào bào zhù cuòwù guāndiǎn bù fàng. Don’t stick to your wrong views. 2 have one&apos;s first child or grandchild 她快抱孙子了。 Tā kuài bào sūnzi le. She’ll soon be a grandmother. 3 adopt (a child) 他的女儿是抱(来)的。 tā de nǚ&apos;ér shì bào de. His daughter is adopted. 4 colloquial hang together 抱成一团 bàochéngyītuán gang up; hang together 5 dialect (of shoes and clothes) fit 这件上衣抱身儿。 Zhè jiàn shàngyī bào shēnr. This jacket fits well. 6 cherish; harbour 抱(有)很大希望 bào hěn dà xīwàng entertain high hopes 抱一线希望 bào yī xiàn xīwàng hope against hope 抱正确的态度 bào zhèngquè de tàidu adopt (or take) a correct attitude; have a good attitude 抱最好的希望, 作最坏的打算 bào zuìhǎo de xīwàng, zuò zuìhuài de dǎsuan hope for the best, but prepare for the worst 不抱幻想 bù bào huànxiǎng cherish no illusions 
measure word armful of 一抱草 yī bào cǎo an armful of hay 这棵树有一抱粗。 zhè kē shù yǒu yī bào cū. You can just get your arms around this tree trunk. 
verb hatch (eggs); brood</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="17288448"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 4"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 4"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="100" difficulty="90" history="25" correct="1" incorrect="1" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903716" lastreviewedtime="1690296485"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689879655"><entry><headword charset="sc">网</headword><headword charset="tc">網</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">wang3</pron><defn>noun 1 net 一张网 yī zhāng wǎng a net 捉蝴蝶的网 zhuō húdié de wǎng butterfly-net 2 network 铁路网 tiělùwǎng railway network 3 web; Internet; net 网上购物 wǎngshàng gòuwù online shopping 上网购物 shàng wǎng gòuwù go shopping on the Internet 
verb 1 catch with a net; net 网鱼 wǎngyú net a fish 被网住 bèi wǎng zhù be caught with a net; entangled 2 cover or enclose as with a net 眼里网着红丝 yǎnlǐ wǎng zhe hóng sī have bloodshot eyes</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="32114688"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 2"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="100" difficulty="88" history="111" correct="0" incorrect="3" reviewed="3" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903766" lastreviewedtime="1690296475"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1689879732" modified="1689879732"><entry><headword charset="sc">照片</headword><headword charset="tc">照片</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zhao4pian1</pron></entry><dictref dictid="1347367491" entryid="124633712"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="1039" difficulty="100" history="55" correct="2" incorrect="0" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903664" lastreviewedtime="1690296496"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689879849"><entry><headword charset="sc">去年</headword><headword charset="tc">去年</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">qu4nian2</pron><defn>noun last year 去年此时 qùnián cǐshí this time last year 去年十二月 qùnián Shí&apos;èryuè last December</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="28803840"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 1"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 2"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="1039" difficulty="100" history="55" correct="2" incorrect="0" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903670" lastreviewedtime="1690296493"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1689879925" modified="1689879925"><entry><headword charset="sc">炸鸡</headword><headword charset="tc">炸雞</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zha2ji1</pron><defn>fried chicken</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="77332523"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="90" history="512" correct="1" incorrect="2" reviewed="3" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903748" lastreviewedtime="1690296457"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1689879943" modified="1689879943"><entry><headword charset="sc">几次</headword><headword charset="tc">幾次</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ji3ci4</pron><defn>several times</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="5968384"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="1039" difficulty="100" history="55" correct="2" incorrect="0" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903773" lastreviewedtime="1690296514"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689879986"><entry><headword charset="sc">办公室</headword><headword charset="tc">辦公室</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ban4gong1shi4</pron><defn>noun 1 office 主任办公室 zhǔrèn bàngōngshì the director’s office 2 administrative department of a unit</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="17137664"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 2"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 3"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="100" difficulty="88" history="15" correct="1" incorrect="1" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903686" lastreviewedtime="1690296504"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1689880032" modified="1689880032"><entry><headword charset="sc">另一</headword><headword charset="tc">另一</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ling4yi1</pron><defn>1 another 2 the other</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="3045888"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="100" difficulty="88" history="15" correct="1" incorrect="1" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903711" lastreviewedtime="1690296511"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689880077"><entry><headword charset="sc">需要</headword><headword charset="tc">需要</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xu1yao4</pron><defn>noun need 从群众的需要出发 Cóng qúnzhòng de xūyào chūfā make the needs of the masses our starting point 适应形势发展的需要 shìyìng xíngshì fāzhǎn de xūyào adapt to the needs of the developing conditions 
verb need; want; require; demand 这本书我非常需要。 Zhè běn shū wǒ fēicháng xūyào. I need this book badly. 这所房子需要修理。 Zhè suǒ fángzi xūyào xiūlǐ. The house wants repairing. 这种情况需要立即采取措施。 Zhèzhǒng qíngkuàng xūyào lìjí cǎiqǔ cuòshī. This situation requires (or demands) immediate action. 坏习惯一旦养成, 需要很长的时间才能根除。 Huài xíguàn yīdàn yǎngchéng, xūyào hěn cháng de shíjiān cái néng gēnchú. A bad habit once contracted takes a very long time to uproot (or root up).</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="33659648"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 3"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 3"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="1039" difficulty="100" history="55" correct="2" incorrect="0" reviewed="2" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1689903695" lastreviewedtime="1690296488"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178463" modified="1689990581"><entry><headword charset="sc">无聊</headword><headword charset="tc">無聊</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">wu2liao2</pron><defn>adjective 1 bored 整天呆在家里, 他感到无聊透了。 Zhěngtiān dāi zài jiālǐ, tā gǎndào wúliáo tòu le. He felt very bored at home all day long. 2 senseless; silly; stupid 不要讲这种无聊的话。 Bùyào jiǎng zhèzhǒng wúliáo de huà. Don’t make such silly remarks.</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="32471808"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 4"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 4"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="100" history="5" correct="1" incorrect="0" reviewed="1" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1690090020" lastreviewedtime="1690090020"/></card><card language="chinese" created="1686178464" modified="1690131813"><entry><headword charset="sc">公寓</headword><headword charset="tc">公寓</headword><pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">gong1yu4</pron><defn>noun 1 apartment; flat; condominium 2 dated lodging house</defn></entry><dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="21724672"/><catassign category="HSK 3.0/Level 7-9"/><catassign category="HSK 2012-2021/Level 5"/><catassign category="Custom"/><scoreinfo scorefile="Default" score="400" difficulty="100" history="5" correct="1" incorrect="0" reviewed="1" sincelast="0" firstreviewedtime="1690296519" lastreviewedtime="1690296519"/></card></cards></plecoflash>